IRINA SARATOVSKAYA



Junior Frontend Developer

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

CONTACT DETAILS:

Date of birth: 26.02.1986
Nationality: Russian

Current residence: Moscow, Russia

www.irinasaratovskaya.com

PROFILE:

Result-oriented professional with 13 years of experience in various areas, including IT and Blockchain projects, working in Business Development & Sales, Software Development, Software Testing and Translation/Localization (English, Korean, and Russian). I am a quick learner who can absorb new ideas and find effective solutions. I have a passion for programming, and I have been honing my skills in side projects (freelance) as well as working on my own applications.

EDUCATION:

2003-2008: Russian State Social University (Russia, Moscow)

Department of foreign languages

Major: Theory and methods of teaching foreign languages and cultures (English, Korean).

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Frontend Development

03/2020 - current

- Part-time Frontend Developer at a Nutrition Technology startup:
 - ✓ Building responsive layouts using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, etc.
 - ✓ Creating forms, interactive UI components
 - ✓ Working with state management, Redux, code refactoring.
 - ✓ Using REST API, CRUD, AJAX
- Working on a personal Fitness app (workout programs and tracking)

Translation and Localization (Freelance)

09/2008 - 03/2020

Five translation/localization agencies in Russia.

- Areas of translation: IT, cryptocurrency, Blockchain, Fintech, marketing & PR, legal, accounting and finance, medicine, etc.
- UI localization of websites, apps, online games, etc. + testing

0.100a.._atto... 0.110a...tcs, apps, 0

08/2019 - 03/2020

Sales & Business Development Manager

AVA Software (IT startup), Singapore

Responsibilities:

- Promoting and selling innovative IT products and services in Southeast Asia, Europe, and the USA (B2B).
- Market research and sales strategy development.
- Assisting in testing new software features.

Key achievements:

I helped to plan and coordinate the development and launch of the company's flagship product, business proposals and communication strategy to attract the first clients, and build partnerships with several major companies in the industry.

CFS Digital (Blockchain, crypto projects), Estonia

08/2017 - 08/2019

Market Specialist & Business Development Manager

Responsibilities:

 Turnkey solutions, ICOs, promotion of Blockchain and Fintech products and services on the global stage, including marketing & PR, community management, IR.

ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS:

08/2019 - current: Front End Development

- Self-education: online courses (400+ hours)
- Professional mentoring (Senior Silicon Valley Developer)

10/2010: The National Institute of Korean Language (Korea)

Educational Program for Experts in Korean Studies.

07/2007 – 08/2007: Gwangju University (Korea)

Korean language training and culture experience program.

06/2006 – 09/2006: Changwon National University (Korea)

Korean language training and culture experience program.

LANGUAGES:

- ✓ English (fluent)
- √ Korean (fluent)
- ✓ Russian (native)

• Translation & localization (English, Korean, and Russian): websites, UI, presentations, Whitepaper, content for blogs, etc.; software testing.

Key achievements:

I helped multiple Blockchain startups adapt their products and services for foreign markets (SEA, Russia, and Europe) and raise over 50,000 BTC on ICOs.

Asia Marine, Ltd. (Luxury Yacht charters), Thailand

11/2016 - 04/2017

Sales Manager

Responsibilities:

- Selling Luxury Yacht charters and coordinating activities within the charter division.
- Preparation of promotional materials, managing the company's website.
 Translation of documents, websites, brochures, etc.

Key achievements:

I attracted the Russian market by establishing partnerships with eight major Russian travel agencies and luxury hotels and villas in Phuket. This provided a continuous flow of customers and therefore increased sales by 30%.

VCP Tour Co., Ltd. (Tourist services), Thailand

05/2014 - 10/2016

Sales and Marketing manager

Responsibilities:

- Selling catamaran private charters & group tours, transfers, spa packages, etc., and developing and maintaining relationships with tour suppliers, hotels, car rental agencies, shops, etc.
- Assisting in developing the company's online booking system and website (translation & localization, testing, creating and updating content).

Key achievements:

I helped to localize the company's products and services (booking system, website, etc.) and attracted the Russian market with which the company had never worked before.

Nuga Medical (Korean medical equipment), Russia

10/2012 - 03/2014

Senior marketing manager/Translator (English, Korean, Russian)

Responsibilities:

- Interpreting (simultaneous, consecutive): lectures, dealer meetings, seminars, conferences. Translation: educational materials (medical field), letters, agreements, etc.
- Organization of dealer conferences (Russia, Turkey), interaction with Russian and foreign travel agencies, development of ad materials.

Key achievements:

I organized and successfully held several large conferences (1000+ participants) in Russia and Turkey, education seminars (250+ people) in Russia.

Daehong Communications (Marketing & PR), Russia

10/2007 - 09/2012

Account manager/Translator (English, Korean, Russian)

Responsibilities:

- Translation and interpreting (company documents, presentations, research results, marketing materials, meetings, conferences).
- Preparation and realization of advertising campaigns.

Key achievements:

I helped increase sales by launching several large advertising campaigns for our major clients.

PROGRAMMING SKILLS:

- JavaScript
- React.js
- Node.js
- HTML, CSS (Bootstrap)
- SQL

TECHNOLOGY TOOLS:

- MS Office
- SmartCAT
- Git, npm
- MemoQ

COLLABORATION TOOLS:

- Jira, Trello
- Asana
- Zoho
- Slack, Zoom
- Pipedrive

PORTFOLIO:

Github profile:

https://github.com/IrinaSaratovskaya